

**CERTIFICATES GIVEN LECTURES EDUCATION INTERESTS** REFERENCES

### SERCAN ÇELENK [EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER]

iZMIR / TURKEY · [+90 530 200 85 02] · SERCANCELENK@GMAIL.COM

"Passionate about IT Profession and Computer Engineering. Have years of experience on Software Development. Designed and building several Softwares with Java, Scala, Ruby, Python. Both had experience in Startups and Enterprise Scale organizations.."









## **EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

**EXPERIENCE** 

#### TRENDYOL TECH GROUP Seller Cargo Invoice, Seller Penalty Invoice, Desi Objection, Product Listing, Customer Invoice

01/2021 - Present

04/2016 - 01/2021

10/2015 - 04/2016

01/2015 - 01/2016

10/2013 - 01/2015

04/2012 - 11/2013

05/2010 - 04/2012

04/2008 - 05/2010

Personal

Turkcell Technology

Turkcell Technology

Dumetech

Personal

09/2003 - 09/2008

✓ Event Driven Architecture ✓ Domain Driven Architecture

✓ Big Data Processing ✓ Apache Kafka Experience

✓ CDC Debezium, Kafka Connect Experienced

✓ Java Streams, Reactive Practices ✓ Postgresql, Couchbase, Redis Experience ✓ Batch Processing Experienced

✓ Clean Code practices ✓ Junit, Mockito , PITest Experienced ✓ Quarkus, Spring Native, GraalVm experienced

✓ Distributed Processing Experienced ✓ Kubernetes, Istio, Gitlab CI ✓ Library Development as Kafka Smart Util, Smart Excel Util, Kafka Shovel

**EXPERT SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY Fizy Music Platform, Magazine Platform, Online Gaming Platform, TV+ Middleware

✓ Core backend development ✓ Reactive Programming with Java 1.8 and projectreactor.io. ✓ Reactive Manifesto, Monads, Functional Programming

✓ Reactive Apache Kafka Cluster Pub/Sub Messaging and Reactive Websocket

✓ Reactive Redis Template, Google Guava Memoizer for in-memory cache ✓ Spring 5 Webflux ✓ Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8 Functional ✓ Redis Cluster, Redis Sentinel

✓ 250000+ connections in one machine on T instant

✓ Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter ✓ Java Concurrency for music content data polling ✓ Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration ✓ Spring Cloud Netflix Microservice Architecture, Spring Boot 2.x, Java 1.8 Functional

✓ Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration ✓ Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache ✓ Replatforming Magazine Core from .Net to Java Microservices

✓ Consul Service Registry, Ribbon, Zuul Filter

✓ Java Concurrency for music content data polling

✓ Redis Cluster, Redis Sentinel

**SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

**SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

**SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER** 

TURKCELL TECHNOLOGY

GLOBAL CAPITAL GROUP ONLINE BANKING COMPANY Project based working in Payment Team.

**HEAD OF CORE DEVELOPMENT** DUMETECH

✓ Spring Boot 1.5, Microservice Architecture, ELK, Zepplin, Zuul Filter, Mockito JUnit

messaging platform via Whatsapp, Viber, Bip. Also we acquire reward from BNP Pariba International Hackhaton in Istanbul.

Dumetech is startup company of us. We developed Mesaj. Ninja Project that online

Eclipse Plugin and Middleware development for Release Management in Turkcell.

AKBANK TECHNOLOGY Main Banking Team, development of financial applications.

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER EG SOFTWARE COMPANY** 

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER** MAG SOFTWARE COMPANY

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

Startup Company, Developed Government Applications and R&D Projects.

#### ✓ Support as retry, filter, low level configuration on yaml files ✓ Support for jdk 11/17, Support for Spring 3.0

**HAZZMON-IO** 

**PROJECTS** 

**SMART KAFKA UTIL** 

Easy kafka integration to your java projects

Turkcell Technology **FLEXDQ - DATA QUALITY TOOL FOR INTEGRATED SYSTEMS** ✓ Spring boot 1.5, Java 1.8, Spring Data, Mysql DB

✓ Spring Quartz Dynamic Job Scheduling ✓ Hazelcast Multicast Distributed Cache ✓ Dockerize modules, Openshift, Jenkins integration

✓ Java 1.7, Spring Data, J2EE, Eclipse Plugin Development, Rest Api ✓ Developed the following modules: Web Api, Schedule Api, Rest Api, Log monitoring Api ✓ Integration of Clearcase and SVN ✓ Eclipse Plugin Development, SWT adapted, Threaded GUI

**DEVELOPER OF SDLC FOR CI / CD AND RELEASE MANAGEMENT PROCESSES** 

✓ Hazelcast Key and Cluster Management Tool ✓ Manage your hazelcast on-demand for your project. Easy setup. ✓ Github: https://github.com/sercancelenk/hazzmon-io ✓ Spring Boot 2.x, Hazelcast Supported All Versions, AngularJs 6 for UI

MESAJ.NINJA - CLOUD MESSAGING APPLICATION VIA WHATSAPP, VIBER ✓ TEB BNP Paribas Hackathon Winner Project ✓ Spring Technologies, Java 1.8, Java concurrency, Ruby Cucumber Integration, AngularJs

✓ From 200+ resources, crawl and serve news data on mobile phone, Mix news with twitter and facebook ✓ Apache Kafka for crawling data on demand, Ruby Sinatra Framework, Solr for indexing and grouping news

**GUNDEM.IN INTELLIGENCE NEWS CRAWLER APPLICATION** 

### Event Driven Architecture Domain Driven Architecture

**SKILLS** 

#### • Java 1.6, 1.7, 1.8, Functional Programming, Design Patterns experience (Advanced) • Dockerize Applications, CI/CD, Jenkins Integrated Applications • Scala for multithreaded processing with functional • Clean code, Microservices Architectures Spring Rest Docs, Mockito, JUnit

• Apache Kafka Messaging (Pub/Sub)

• Big Data Processing on kafka

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & TOOLS

• Ruby (Intermediate) - Sinatra, Rails Frameworks WORKFLOW

• Spring Data, Rest, Webflux, Oauth, Hibernate, JWT (Advanced)

• Scala for multithreaded processing with functional

• Redis Sentinel, Redis Server Cluster, Sharding

• Hazelcast Cluster, Google Guava, Ehcache

• Reactive Programming, Reactive Manifesto, Scalable Systems

✓ Accept and Analyze Problem ✓ Find most suitable solution ✓ Develop most efficiently ✓ Agile Development & Scrum

# **AWARDS & CERTIFICATIONS**

\* Spring Framework Architecture (2013) (kodcu.com)

JavaSE and Design Patterns (2007) (Oracle)

\* Oracle OCA Certificate (2011) (Oracle-Ireland)

# Java 1.8 New fetures (2015) (Oracle)

# Java EE (2013-2014) - Oracle

**GIVEN LECTURES** 

✓ Startup Roadmap (I.T.U Cekirdek)

뭇 (Mesaj.Ninja Project) BNP Paribas & TEB International Hackhaton Winner in ISTANBUL (2015)

✓ Reactive Programming (Turkcell Technology) ✓ Java 1.8 New features (Turkcell Technology) ✓ Sql Tuning (Bilge Adam)

## **EDUCATION**

## **ENGINEERING FACULTY - COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT**

**SELÇUK UNIVERSITY** 

**INTERESTS** 

## Graduated.

• Professionally, I like to constantly develop myself, create other fields, learn other languages, produce new ideas and projects.

• In my free time I like playing guitar, playing football, driving a car, and reading politics.

- REFERENCES

• References will be supplied in case of request.